WE WENT TO THE BEACH.
PHOEBE FOUND THIS LADY
WHO KNEW HER PARENTS.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THAT.
I'M YOUR MOTHER.
HUH?
MONICA JOKED SHE WOULDN'T
GO OUT WITH
A GUY LIKE CHANDLER.
HE COULDN'T LET IT GO.
I DON'T KNOW
WHAT HAPPENED WITH THAT.
THEN ROSS'S NEW GIRLFRIEND,
BONNIE, SHOWS UP
AND RACHEL CONVINCED HER
TO SHAVE HER HEAD.
THEN ROSS AND RACHEL KISS.
ROSS HAS TO CHOOSE
BETWEEN RACHEL
AND THE BALD GIRL...
AND I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED
THERE, EITHER.
LET ME GO GET CHANDLER.
HI.
HEY.
RACHEL WAS JUST
HELPING ME OUT.
MY HEAD GOT
ALL SUNBURNED.
AW.
THANKS A MILLION.
OH, YOU'RE WELCOME
A MILLION.
OKAY, I'LL BE
IN OUR ROOM.
OH, MY GOD.
I KNOW.
OKAY, I GOT TO GO.
WHAT? WHAT?
I GOT TO GO
BREAK UP WITH BONNIE.
HERE? NOW?
WELL, YEAH.
I CAN'T STAY HERE
ALL NIGHT.
IF I GO IN THERE,
SHE'LL WANT TO...
DO STUFF.
CAN'T YOU JUST TELL HER
THAT YOU ARE NOT IN THE MOOD?
NO, SHE LIKES THAT.
FAKING SLEEP
DOESN'T WORK, EITHER.
I CAN'T TELL YOU HOW MANY
MORNINGS I WOKE UP WITH HER...
EW.
OKAY.
WHY AM I TELLING
YOU THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
UH...
IT WASN'T EVERY MORNING...
MAKING IT WORSE.
OKAY.
♪ SO NO ONE TOLD YOU
LIFE WAS GONNA BE THIS WAY ♪
♪ YOUR JOB'S A JOKE,
YOU'RE BROKE ♪
♪ YOUR LOVE LIFE'S D.O.A. ♪
♪ IT'S LIKE YOU'RE ALWAYS
STUCK IN SECOND GEAR ♪
♪ WHEN IT HASN'T BEEN YOUR DAY ♪
♪ YOUR WEEK, YOUR MONTH,
OR EVEN YOUR YEAR ♪
♪ BUT I'LL BE THERE FOR YOU ♪
♪ WHEN THE RAIN
STARTS TO POUR ♪
♪ I'LL BE THERE FOR YOU ♪
♪ LIKE I'VE BEEN THERE BEFORE ♪
♪ 'CAUSE YOU'RE THERE
FOR ME TOO. ♪
I GUESS YOU'D LIKE
TO KNOW HOW IT ALL HAPPENED.
I-I MEAN, I THINK
I CAN FIGURE IT OUT.
I GUESS I WAS BORN
AND THEN, EVERYONE STARTED
LYING THEIR ASSES OFF.
NO, NO.
IT WASN'T LIKE THAT.
REMEMBER HOW I TOLD YOU
HOW LILY AND FRANK AND I
WERE CLOSE?
WELL, WE WERE VERY CLOSE.
HOW CLOSE?
WELL, THE THREE OF US
WE WERE KIND OF A COUPLE.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW HOW
THAT WOULD WORK.
WELL, WE WOULD...
I'M NOT ASKING.
WELL, ANYHOW,
SOMEHOW, I GOT PREGNANT
AND I WAS...
SCARED.
I WAS STUPID AND SELFISH AND...
I WAS 18 YEARS OLD.
I MEAN, YOU REMEMBER
WHAT IT WAS LIKE
TO BE 18 YEARS OLD, DON'T YOU?
YEAH.
LET'S SEE...
MY MOM HAD KILLED HERSELF
AND MY DAD HAD RUN OFF
AND I WAS LIVING IN A GREMLIN
WITH A GUY NAMED CINDY
WHO TALKED
TO HIS HAND.
OH, I'M SO SORRY.
I THOUGHT I WAS LEAVING YOU
WITH THE BEST PARENTS
IN THE WORLD.
I DIDN'T EVEN HEAR
ABOUT YOUR MOM AND DAD
TILL A COUPLE
OF YEARS AGO.
BY THEN, YOU WERE
ALREADY GROWN UP
AND, I DON'T KNOW,
YOU'RE HERE
AND I WOULD REALLY...
I WOULD LIKE
TO GET TO KNOW YOU.
YEAH, WELL, EVERYBODY DOES.
I'M A REALLY COOL PERSON.
AND, YOU KNOW, YOU HAD
29 YEARS TO FIND THAT OUT
BUT YOU DIDN'T EVEN TRY.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU WALKED OUT ON ME.
I'M DOING THE SAME TO YOU.
WAIT...
I DON'T EVER WANT
TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
( sighs )
WHERE'S MY PURSE?
SHOOT. WE'RE OUT
OF SODA.
I'LL GO OUT
AND GET YOU SOME.
REALLY?
NOPE, 'CAUSE I'M NOT
YOUR BOYFRIEND.
HEY, PHEEBS,
HOW DID IT GO?
WELL...
MY MOM'S FRIEND, PHOEBE
IS ACTUALLY MY BIRTH MOM.
I FOUND A DRIED-UP SEA HORSE.
SWEETIE,
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
OH, MY NEW MOM
WHO'S A BIG, FAT ABANDONER.
WELL, PHEEBS,
WAIT A SECOND.
DON'T YOU WANT TO STAY HERE
AND TALK ABOUT IT?
NO. I WANT...
I NEED
TO BE ALONE.
MONICA?!
OH.
IT'S OVER.
OH, WAS IT AWFUL?
WELL, IT WAS LONG.
I DIDN'T EVEN REALIZE
HOW LATE IT WAS
TILL I NOTICED
THE 5:00 SHADOW
ON HER HEAD.
( stifled laugh )
ANYWAY, SHE DIDN'T
WANT TO STAY.
I CALLED A CAB.
SHE JUST LEFT.
I WROTE YOU A LETTER.
OH, THANK YOU.
I LIKE MAIL.
THERE'S JUST...
YOU KNOW, SOME THINGS
I'VE BEEN THINKING ABOUT--
THINGS ABOUT US--
AND BEFORE
I CAN EVEN THINK ABOUT
THE TWO OF US
GETTING BACK TOGETHER
I JUST NEED TO KNOW
HOW YOU FEEL
ABOUT THIS STUFF.
OKAY.
IT'S...
IT'S 5:30 IN THE MORNING.
SO... I BETTER GET
CRACKING ON THIS BABY.
SO, I'LL BE WAITING FOR YOU.
JUST COME UP WHEN YOU'RE DONE.
OKAY.
I'LL BE UP IN...
18 PAGES.
FRONT AND BACK.
IT'S VERY EXCITING.
OH, OH, OH.
HEY.
WHAT HAPPENED TO YOU?
WHY DIDN'T YOU
COME UP?
DONE.
YOU JUST FINISHED?
WELL, I WANTED
TO BE THOROUGH.
I MEAN, THIS IS CLEARLY
VERY, VERY IMPORTANT
TO YOU...
TO US.
SO I WANTED TO READ
EVERY WORD CAREFULLY...
TWICE.
SO, UM...
DOES IT?
I'M SORRY?
YEAH, I WANTED TO GIVE
THAT WHOLE "DOES IT" PART
JUST ANOTHER GLANCE.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU SAID
YOU READ IT TWICE.
LOOK, IT EITHER
DOES OR IT DOESN'T
AND IF YOU HAVE
TO EVEN THINK ABOUT IT...
NO, NO, RACH,
NO, I DON'T.
I DON'T HAVE TO THINK
ABOUT IT. I DON'T.
IN FACT...
I'VE DECIDED.
I HAVE DECIDED THAT...
THAT IT...
DOES.
( sniffling )
ARE YOU SURE?
SURE, I'M SURE.
ALL RIGHT, THERE'S
A NUCLEAR HOLOCAUST.
I'M THE LAST MAN ON EARTH.
WOULD YOU GO OUT WITH ME?
EHH.
I'VE GOT CANNED GOODS.
HEY, GUYS, TAKE A LOOK
AT THIS.
CHECK THIS BABY OUT.
DUG ME A HOLE.
EXCELLENT HOLE, JOE.
OH, NO!
MY HOLE!
OW! OW!
WHAT IS IT?
JELLYFISH STING!
IT HURTS! IT HURTS!
CAN WE HELP YOU?
YOU WANT US TO TAKE YOU
BACK TO THE HOUSE?
IT'S LIKE TWO MILES.
AND I'M A LITTLE TIRED
FROM DIGGING THE HOLE.
OW! OW!
DAMN THE JELLYFISH!
DAMN ALL THE JELLYFISH!
WE'VE GOT
TO DO SOMETHING.
THERE'S ONLY ONE THING
YOU CAN DO.
WHAT? WHAT IS IT?
YOU HAVE TO PEE ON IT.
WHAT?!
GROSS!
DON'T BLAME ME.
I SAW IT
ON THE DISCOVERY CHANNEL.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
HE'S RIGHT.
THERE'S SOMETHING
LIKE AMMONIA IN THAT
THAT KILLS THE PAIN.
WELL, FORGET IT.
IT DOESN'T HURT THAT...
BAD!
IF YOU WANT SOME PRIVACY,
YOU CAN USE MY HOLE.
WELL, I'M READY
TO GET THE HELL OUT OF HERE.
OH...
ARE YOU..?
ARE YOU?!
OH, THAT'S SO GREAT!
OOH, NOT FOR BONNIE.
BUT FOR YOU, YAY.
HEY.
Rachel:
HOW WAS THE BEACH?
NOTHING. I DON'T KNOW.
( mumbling )
WHAT
HAPPENED?
NOTHING.
I'M GOING TO TAKE
A SHOWER.
ME, TOO.
OKAY, I'M GOING TO PUT
THIS IN THE CAR.
OH, I HAVE
TO GO PACK.
OH.
AND IT REALLY DOES?
IT DOES.
IT REALLY AND TRULY DOES.
IT SO DOES NOT!
SHE WANTS ME
TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY
FOR EVERYTHING THAT WENT WRONG
IN OUR RELATIONSHIP.
I MEAN, SHE GOES ON
FOR FIVE PAGES
ABOUT HOW I WAS
UNFAITHFUL TO HER.
WE WERE ON A BREAK!
OH, MY GOD!
IF YOU SAY THAT ONE MORE TIME
I'LL BREAK UP WITH YOU.
FINE, FINE. BUT THIS BREAKUP
WAS NOT ALL MY FAULT
AND SHE SAYS HERE
"IF YOU ACCEPT FULL
RESPONSIBILITY..."
FULL RESPONSIBILITY!
"I CAN BEGIN TO TRUST YOU AGAIN.
"DOES THAT SEEM LIKE
SOMETHING YOU CAN DO?
DOES IT?!"
NO?
YOU HAVE WHAT YOU WANT.
YOU'RE BACK WITH RACHEL.
IF YOU BRING THIS UP NOW
YOU'LL WRECK THE BEST THING
THAT EVER HAPPENED TO YOU.
YEAH, I KNOW.
YOU'RE RIGHT.
( sighs )
YEAH, I GUESS
I'LL LET IT GO.
BUT YOU... YOU UNDERSTAND
HOW HARD IT IS
TO FORGET ABOUT THIS.
SURE, IT'S HARD
TO FORGET
BUT THAT DOESN'T MEAN YOU
HAVE TO TALK ABOUT IT.
A LOT OF THINGS HAPPENED
ON THAT TRIP
THAT WE SHOULD NEVER,
EVER TALK ABOUT.
WHAT THE HELL HAPPENED
ON THAT BEACH?
IT'S BETWEEN US
AND THE SEA, ROSS.
HI, URSULA.
HEY.
OKAY, WELL, I KNOW
THAT WE HAVEN'T TALKED
IN A LONG TIME
BUT, UM, OKAY...
OUR MOM IS NOT OUR BIRTH MOM.
THIS OTHER LADY
IS OUR BIRTH MOM.
RIGHT. OKAY. THE ONE THAT
LIVES IN MONTAUK. MM-HMM.
YOU KNOW HER?
NO. I, UM, I READ ABOUT HER
IN MOM'S SUICIDE NOTE.
THERE WAS A SUICIDE NOTE?
WELL, DO YOU STILL HAVE IT?
HANG ON.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME
THERE WAS A SUICIDE NOTE.
YEAH. SO HOW HAVE
YOU BEEN DOING?
I'VE... UH... SHUT UP.
"GOOD-BYE, PHOEBE AND URSULA.
"I'LL MISS YOU.
P.S. YOUR MOM
LIVES IN MONTAUK."
YOU JUST WROTE THIS!
WELL, IT'S PRETTY
MUCH THE GIST.
WELL, EXCEPT FOR THE POEM.
YOU READ THE POEM, RIGHT?
NO.
ALL RIGHT. HANG ON.
PASS THE CHEESE, PLEASE.
( groans )
MY GOD, YOU CAN'T EVEN
LOOK AT ME, CAN YOU?
NOPE.
HEY,
IT'S PHOEBE!
WE CAN TALK TO PHOEBE!
NO. I'M TOO
DEPRESSED TO TALK.
I'LL GIVE YOU $1,000
TO TALK TO US.
HEY, YOU GUYS,
WHAT DO YOU THINK
ABOUT MAKING THAT BEACH TRIP
AN ANNUAL THING?
NO!
ALL RIGHT,
WHAT HAPPENED
OUT THERE?
WHAT?
WE TOOK A WALK.
NOTHING HAPPENED.
AND I CAME BACK
WITH NOTHING ALL OVER ME.
COME ON, WHAT HAPPENED?
JOEY?
ALL RIGHT.
NO!
JOEY, WE SWORE
WE'D NEVER TELL.
THEY'LL NEVER UNDERSTAND.
WELL, WE HAVE
TO SAY SOMETHING.
WE HAVE TO GET IT OUT.
IT'S EATING ME ALIVE!
MONICA GOT STUNG
BY A JELLYFISH.
ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT.
I GOT STUNG.
STUNG BAD.
I COULDN'T STAND.
I... I COULDN'T WALK.
WE WERE TWO MILES
FROM THE HOUSE.
WE WERE SCARED AND ALONE.
WE DIDN'T THINK
WE COULD MAKE IT.
I WAS IN TOO MUCH PAIN.
AND I WAS TIRED
FROM DIGGING THE HUGE HOLE.
AND THEN, JOEY
REMEMBERED SOMETHING.
I'D SEEN THIS THING
ON THE DISCOVERY CHANNEL.
WAIT A MINUTE.
I SAW THAT.
ON THE DISCOVERY CHANNEL.
YEAH, ABOUT JELLYFISH,
AND HOW IF YOU...
EWW!
YOU PEED
ON YOURSELF?
EWW!
YOU CAN'T SAY THAT!
YOU DON'T KNOW!
I MEAN, I THOUGHT
I WOULD PASS OUT
FROM THE PAIN.
ANYWAY, I TRIED...
BUT I COULDN'T...
BEND THAT WAY.
SO...
EWW!
THAT'S RIGHT, I STEPPED UP!
SHE'S MY FRIEND,
AND SHE NEEDED HELP.
IF I HAD TO,
I'D PEE ON ANY ONE OF YOU.
ONLY, UH...
I COULDN'T.
I GOT THE STAGE FRIGHT.
I WANTED TO HELP
BUT THERE WAS JUST
TOO MUCH PRESSURE
SO... SO I, UH...
I TURNED TO CHANDLER.
( muffled scream )
JOEY KEPT SCREAMING AT ME
"DO IT NOW!
DO IT! DO IT!
DO IT NOW!"
SOMETIMES, LATE AT NIGHT
I CAN STILL HEAR
THE SCREAMING.
( chuckling )
THAT'S 'CAUSE SOMETIMES
I JUST DO IT THROUGH MY WALL
TO FREAK YOU OUT.
Phoebe:
♪ ...AND FUCHSIA AND MAUVE ♪
♪ THOSE ARE THE 66 COLORS
OF MY BEDROOM. ♪
( sparse applause )
THANK YOU.
OH, AND I INVITE ALL OF YOU
TO COUNT THE COLORS IN
YOURBEDROOM.
EXCEPT FOR YOU.
YOU GO AWAY.
I'LL GO IN A SECOND.
I JUST WANT TO TELL YOU
THAT THERE
HASN'T BEEN A DAY
WHEN I DIDN'T REGRET
GIVING YOU UP.
OKAY. BYE.
NO. I'M NOT DONE.
I JUST WANT YOU TO KNOW
THAT THE REASON I NEVER
LOOKED YOU UP WAS BECAUSE...
WELL, I WAS AFRAID
THAT YOU WOULD REACT...
JUST, WELL, LIKE THE WAY
YOU'RE REACTING RIGHT NOW
AND... CAN'T WE JUST
YOU KNOW, START
FROM HERE, PLEASE?
NO.
OKAY.
SORRY.
BUT JUST ONE LAST THING.
YOU KNOW, YOU CAME
LOOKING FOR FAMILY.
I'M FAMILY.
( sighs )
I'M IT.
WELL, NOW I'M DONE.
BUT IT'S NOT LIKE WE'RE
LOSING ANYTHING, YOU KNOW?
YEAH, I GUESS YOU'RE RIGHT.
IT'S NOT LIKE WE KNOW
EACH OTHER OR ANYTHING
OR THAT WE HAVE
ANYTHING IN COMMON.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW.
I MEAN, IT'S NOT LIKE
WE DON'T HAVE
ANYTHING IN COMMON.
I MEAN, I LIKE PIZZA.
I... I LIKE PIZZA.
YOU DO! HA!
WAIT, I LIKE, UM, THE BEATLES.
OH, MY GOD, SO DO I!
OH, I KNEW IT!
WOW!
WAIT-WAIT-WAIT.
PUPPIES-- CUTE OR UGLY?
OH, SO CUTE.
UH-HUH! WELL?
YOU SEE?
BUT I'M STILL... I'M MAD AT YOU.
I KNOW.
I'M MAD AT ME, TOO.
WELL, UM, DO YOU WANT
TO GET SOMETHING TO EAT?
'CAUSE I'M
KIND OF HUNGRY.
HEY! ME, TOO!
STOP IT.
NOW YOU'RE JUST DOING IT
TO FREAK ME OUT.
( deep sigh )
OH, I MISSED YOU.
I MISSED YOU, TOO.
OH, I WAS SO NERVOUS
ABOUT THAT LETTER.
BUT THE WAY YOU
OWNED UP TO EVERYTHING
IT JUST... SHOWED ME
HOW MUCH YOU'VE
GROWN, YOU KNOW?
I SUPPOSE.
NO, YOU HAVE,
ROSS, YOU HAVE.
YOU SHOULD GIVE
YOURSELF CREDIT.
I MEAN, MY MOM NEVERTHOUGHT
THIS WOULD WORK OUT.
( chuckling )
SHE WAS ALL,
"ONCE A CHEATER,
ALWAYS A CHEATER."
MM-HMM.
OH... I JUST WISH
WE HADN'T LOST
THOSE FOUR MONTHS.
BUT IF TIME WAS
WHAT YOU NEEDED
JUST TO GAIN A
LITTLE PERSPECTIVE...
Ross:
WE WERE
ON A BREAK!
COFFEE HOUSE?
YOU BET.
AND FOR THE RECORD,
IT TOOK TWO PEOPLE
TO BREAK UP
THIS RELATIONSHIP.
YOU AND THAT GIRL
FROM THE COPY PLACE
WHICH, YESTERDAY, YOU TOOK
FULL RESPONSIBILITY FOR.
I DIDN'T KNOW WHAT I WAS
TAKING RESPONSIBILITY FOR, OKAY?
I DIDN'T FINISH
THE WHOLE LETTER.
WHAT?
I FELL ASLEEP.
YOU FELL ASLEEP?
IT WAS 5:30 IN THE MORNING
AND YOU HAD RAMBLED ON
FOR 18 PAGES.
FRONT AND BACK!
( groans )
OH-OH-OH, AND BY THE WAY
Y-O-U APOSTROPHE R-E
MEANS "YOU ARE."
Y-O-U-R MEANS "YOUR."
HA! YOU KNOW,
I CAN'T BELIEVE
I EVEN THOUGHT OF GETTING
BACK TOGETHER WITH YOU.
WE ARE SO OVER.
( choked up ):
OH... OH... OH...
FINE BY ME!
OH, AND HEY, THOSE
LITTLE SPELLING TIPS
WILL COME IN HANDY
WHEN YOU'RE AT HOME
ON SATURDAY NIGHTS
PLAYING SCRABBLE
WITH MONICA!
HEY...
SORRY!
I JUST FEEL BAD
ABOUT ALL THAT SLEEP
YOU'RE GOING TO MISS
WISHING YOU
WERE WITH ME.
OH, NO-NO-NO, DON'T YOU WORRY
ABOUT ME FALLING ASLEEP.
I STILL HAVE YOUR LETTER!
AND HEY, JUST SO YOU KNOW...
IT'S NOT THAT COMMON
IT DOESN'T HAPPEN TO EVERY GUY
AND IT IS A BIG DEAL!
I KNEW IT!
GIN.
WE WERE PLAYING GIN?
YOU KNOW,
IF WE WERE A COUPLE
WE COULD PLAY THIS GAME NAKED.
( laughing )
WOULD YOU STOP?
OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, ALL RIGHT.
I THINK YOU'RE GREAT.
I THINK YOU'RE SWEET
AND YOU'RE SMART
AND I LOVE YOU.
BUT YOU WILL
ALWAYS BE THE GUY
WHO PEED ON ME.
[Captioned by
The Caption Center
WGBH Educational Foundation]